KEN TAUCHI

FRONT FND DEVELOPER

contact

6

(604) 250-4189



kentauchi.jb@gmail.com github.com/KenTauchi



linkedin.com/in/kentauchi



kentauchi-portfolio.vercel.app



about me

A front end web developer with practical knowledge and experience of application design and delivery, through professional and freelance projects. Continual development of strong communication through client interaction and debugging of website plug-ins for clients and collaborative projects. Always pushing to further develop technical skills by self-education and group critique.

professional experience

Full Stack Developer

Langara College / Vancouver, BC / 2020 - Present

- Remodeled college program website with React, which increased the demand for new website creation for other college departments.
- Adapted the website through dynamically fetching content from APIs. This made the website scalable, as uploading new material that is formatted to the design, does not require coding knowledge.
- Leveraged CSS functions to style for various devices with a variety of mockup. This workflow helped the design team focus on a sprint backlog, and created a collaborative team environment.
- Presented weekly deliverables in every sprint review, which enhanced the effective communication with the designers.
- Proposed an alternative development solution to the supervisor by considering available resources and production lead time. This helped the project meet a shortened deadline.

Account Executive

Criteo / Tokyo, Japan / 2017 - 2019

- Built a relationship with a company by proposing a customized advertisement campaign according to their needs, resulting in a three times higher budget increase than originally planned.
- Prioritized clients to approach by forecasting the amount of profit each client could potentially generate, based on their budget and website scale.
- Mentored co-workers by teaching them how to approach potential clients, resulting in their higher percentage of the new client acquisition rate.

education

Post Degree Diploma Web & Mobile App Development Langara College,

Vancouver Jan 2020 - Apr 2021

Bachelor of Business Administration

Dual Degree Program American University, Washington, D.C. Ritsumeikan University, Osaka, Japan Aug 2010 - Jul 2014

tech skills

HTML / CSS / Sass

JavaScript

React / Redux / Hooks

React Native

Git and Version Control

Node.js / Express

API

MySQL / Firebase

project experience

Lead Frontend Developer - Project "Savy"

Langara College / Vancouver / Fall 2020

An educational data driven responsive platform that aims to help people who are concerned about our environment to get more information about recycling.

- Self-taught React Redux and Hooks, and shared the knowledge with other team developers, making the platform to be more interactive.
- Implemented an interactive Canada map on which users can find province information on click, with React Redux and the amChart library. This reinforced the user engagement, as user testing data indicated.
- Developed a quiz game with React Redux and CSS using API for the questions and answers that teaches the user about recycling in Canada.
- Effectively communicated with the backend developers to maximize the efficiency of client-side rendering, which maintained the fast page loading speed and increased user interaction with the web app.

Frontend Developer - Project "Nearest"

Langara College / Vancouver / Summer 2020

A mobile app which helps locate the closest available public washrooms.

- Visualized public restroom locations and the user's current location on a map by fetching latitude and longitude data through an API, which helps the user find the nearest restroom at a glance.
- Implemented a screen where users can find unique information about the restroom they select on a map with JavaScript and the Firebase queries.
- Created a function with JavaScript which enables the user to post a new restroom location on a map by interacting with Firebase. This increased the efficiency in the app maintainability and future scalability.

volunteer experience

Technical Assistant

Impro Kids Tokyo/ Tokyo / 2020 - present

Integrated a notification tool sent to Slack into sales order documents and surveys created with Google Forms to complete an enhanced client list. Those modifications led to quick customer service, on the company's platform.

Goodwill Ambassador

National Cherry Blossom Festival / Washington D.C. / 2012 Spring

Presented the history of the cherry trees as well as Japanese language and culture to children as cultural and educational liaisons, contributing to childhood education in cultural diversity, with an interactive activity.

certifications

Dean's Honor Roll *Langara College*2020 Spring, Summer and Fall

language

Japanese Native Level Speaking, Writing & Reading